Christopher J. Smith - Senior Software Engineer

csmith4work@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I am a passionate software engineer with over 5 years of experience working in every capacity of the software development lifecycle. Specializing in Full Stack Development, I've gathered requirements, architected solutions, implemented code, curated tests and managed the release and updates of various products and tools. I've learned that I excel in working at the forefront of technology, providing my skills to help create new solutions and integrations where none existed before. I value gathering all the relevant context and requirements for a project, consistent communication, managing expectations and proper documentation and project management. This ensures that my software delivery can be as robust as possible while also maintaining efficiency during the development process.

Core Skills

- Application and Web Development: C#, Dotnet, Python, Node.JS, Vue, Nuxt.JS, React.JS, Type-script, GraphQL, JQuery, SASS
- · Cloud Infrastructure: AWS, Terraform, IAM
- Compute Infrastructure and Tooling: EC2, Docker, ECR, ECS, Lambda, Kubernetes, Helm, Heroku
- Software Integration: SNS, SQS, Stripe, RioSEO, Airtable, Contentful, FFMPEG, Google API, Infor
- Data Storage: S3, SQL Server, MongoDB, Postgres, RDS, DynamoDb
- Automation: YAML, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, Github Actions, CircleCl, Spacelift, Secrets Manager, Parameter Store, Jenkins
- Testing Frameworks: Jest, Puppeteer, Artillery, XUnit, SpecFlow
- Networking: Route53, Cloudflare, Cloudfront, VPC, NGINX
- · Scripting: Python, Bash, Git
- Monitoring and Alerting: New Relic, Opsgenie, CloudWatch, Sentry, Google Analytics
- Project Tracking and Documentation: Jira, Confluence, Notion, LucidChart, Asana

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics - May 2016, Tennessee State University

Professional Experience

Senior Application Engineer @ HCA

April 2023 - present

- Managed project complexity and enhanced my ability to consistently switch between contexts as I was entrusted to contribute to 4 dashboards that covered 3 different initiatives.
- Refactored and reviewed the design of a new internal dashboard written in React.JS. Gave input to management on best practices and how to better adhere to software design principles in development.
- Integrated a new React homepage for employees with third-party services and APIs using their provided API Gateway created by Infor.
- Mentored and assisted junior developers with application development, providing documentation, personal experience and code reviews to help develop growth and reinforce software best practices. Pair programming regularly with developers.

Cloud Platform Engineer II @ Butterfly Network

Dec 2021 - Jan 2023

- Spearheaded the architecting of a system-wide monitoring and alerting system, seamlessly integrating AWS Route 53 Health Checks with NewRelic and Opsgenie.
- Championed the deployment of a brand new mobile Proof of Concept (POC) onto an established Kubernetes architecture leveraging Helm, Github Actions, and Terraform.
- Successfully orchestrated the migration of an e-commerce frontend from a legacy AWS architecture to a modern setup, taking the lead in configuring and maintaining the front-end using Cloudfront.
- Collaboratively steered over 20 application deployments to staging and production environments using CircleCI.
- Led a dynamic team in a Hackathon, innovating, testing, and presenting metrics for a robust load testing framework employing Artillery.
- Diligently participated in a 24x7 on-call rotation, providing unwavering support to the newly instituted Kubernetes architecture.
- Authored and presented several pivotal Architecture Design documents to a Design Review committee, ensuring alignment and approval before project execution.

Junior Software Engineer @ SmileDirectClub

March 2019 - Dec 2021

- Dismantled 3 parts of the company's monolithic e-commerce application into microservices in an agile development environment using scrum and kanban methodologies.
- Implemented microservices using .Net Core and DynamoDb. Deployed services through CI/CD pipeline consisting of Jenkins, Docker, AWS and Terraform.
- Wrote frontend and backend unit and integration tests. Integrated the tests into the CI/CD pipeline.
- Integrated a microservice with RioSEO third party API in order to automate a business need, saving the company at least \$50,000/year in manual data entry. Added components to, maintained and refactored components in company Component Library using Vue.js and Bootstrap.
- Developed MicroUI in Vue.js that integrated with Google Maps API and configured UI to be deployed as a CMS plugin via npm.

Freelance Software Engineer @ Nashville, TN

August 2017 - present

- Designed, implemented, hosted and maintained a media production marketing website using Node.js, Vue.js, AWS and Heroku. Integrated application with Contentful and Airtable.
- Designed, implemented and tested an E-Commerce website developed in .Net Core and JQuery, integrated with Stripe.
- Fully implemented a POC for a custom pre-designed web application in .Net Core with booking and scheduling functionality.

Software Developer Associate @ Accenture

June 2016 - August 2017

- Managed defects, tests, and executed test cases for a monolithic application using Microsoft Test Manager and Microsoft Team Foundation Server.
- Designed and implemented a solution in C# that records application transactions into the respective database.
- Completed Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist certification and demonstrated its automation features.